Marcin Ciunelis

Experienced Ruby (on Rails) programmer

Summary

I am a software engineer with more than 10 years of professional experience in designing, development, maintaining and scaling various internet applications from small startups to fast growing ones. I like to deliver simple, extensible and well designed software. I don't believe in silver bullet solutions. I love experimenting, learning from mistakes and iterating over a software to get closer to the perfect code. Refactoring is my hobby.

Skills

I have professional experience with technologies including:

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Swift, PostgreSql, Elasticsearch, Redis, Javascript, Coffescript, jQuery, Backbone, Ember, react, PhoneGap, Capistrano, AWS, Chef, Docker

Technologies that I used in my hobby projects:

Objective-C & Swift for iOs & MacOS apps, Node.is, GithubAPI

Work Experience

Software Engineer (Ruby/Javascript/Swift), Rebased, Warsaw (remote); 2015 - present

At Rebased I was delegated to work as a part of client's team. I was attending remotely daily stand-ups, meetings, etc. Projects that I worked on includes:

- API and internal tools for company providing private transportation service all over the
 world. It's a legacy app that now is being rewritten to around twenty micro services.
 My team is responsible for maintaining the legacy app and handling pricing, payments,
 invoicing & fraud preventing. Technologies used: Ruby on Rails 5, MySQL,
 PostgreSQL, SQS, SNS.
- Internal Rebased tool for team management (holidays, assignments, work load)
- Rewrite to EmberJS legacy javascript app for media publishers.
- iOS app for reading books published in parts. Written from scratch in Swift.
- Proof of concept web app for musicians reaching publishers. Build from scratch with Ruby on Rails 5 and React.
- Charity organization providing course materials used in more than 100 schools across UK. I was working on maintaining and improving education platform on daily basis and migrated it from Ruby on Rails 3 to version 4.

Software Engineer (Ruby/Javascript), <u>jobandtalent.com</u>, Warsaw/Barcelona (remote)

2012 - 2015

jobandtalent is Europe's first Social Media Recruitment Platform. I was working on:

- REST API & documentation used by Backbone (mobile), iOs & Android clients
- Mobile Web version single page app using Backbone and Lungo.js
- extraction of various micro services from the platform.
- refactor messy javascript to backbone views and models
- PhoneGap mobile app using Backbone, Coffeescript deployed to App Store, Google Play & mobile web
- 3rd party services integration for push notifications, sms, geo service, gender guessing

phone.+48 501 009 207 email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com linkedin: linkedin.com/in/martinciu github: github.com/martinciu location: Warsaw, Poland

- · payment gateway integrations PayU Latam, Stripe
- Facebook & LinkedIn integrations & profile imports
- · migrate search engine to Elasticsearch
 - setup Elasticsearch cluster on EC2 with Chef
 - tweaking tire client gem
- new features, bug fixes, pull request review, platform planning
- whole platform rewrite from Rails 2 to Rails 3

Software Engineer (Ruby) & Co-founder, zubibu.com, Gdansk, Poland 2010 - 2011

Zubibu was a SaaS m-commerce solution for online retailers. I was responsible for all backend architecture, and programming, public REST API and documentation. We were scraping hundreds of e-shops and/or their XML data feed processing millions of items on daily basics. Technologies used include: Ruby on Rails 3.1, MongoDB, Redis, Solr, Amazon EC2, S3, Cloudfront, Resque. It is no longer maintained.

Software Engineer & Partner (Ruby/PHP), G-Forces Web Management Polska; Gdansk, Poland

2006 - 2009

Responsible for developing custom systems for clients - CRMs, CMSes and e-commerce solutions. Technologies used: Ruby on Rails 2&3, PHP5, MySql, PostgreSql.

Software Engineer (PHP), G-Forces Web Management Ltd; Maidstone, United Kingdom

2005 - 2006

G-Forces is a major web development company from Kent, UK specialized in automotive and e-commerce software. I was responsible for developing custom systems for clients - CRMs, CMSes and e-commerce solutions. Technologies used: PHP5, MySql, PostgreSql.

Freelance PHP developer, self-employed; Poland 2004 - 2005

I worked with several clients on custom CMS, CRM and e-commerce systems.

Internet Specialist/PHP developer, Troll Sp. z o.o.; Sopot, Poland 2002 - 2004

Troll was a major clothing company in Poland. I was responsible for all company presence in the Internet - managing website, coordinating offline experience with online, marketing campaigns etc. I also worked on several internal system for managing warehouse, e-commerce site and B2B solution.

Open Source Contributions

Errbit, contributor

The open source error catcher that's Airbrake API compliant

I worked on performance optimization, errors matching improvements and refactoring

https://github.com/errbit/errbit

nullobject, creator

Null Object Design Pattern Ruby implementation https://github.com/martinciu/nullobject

phone.+48 501 009 207
email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com
linkedin: linkedin.com/in/martinciu
github: github.com/martinciu
location: Warsaw, Poland

tire, contributor

A rich Ruby API and DSL for the Elasticsearch search engine I've added support for script fields, field boost and lazy load attributes https://github.com/karmi/retire

Lungo.js, contributor

A HTML5 framework for your mobile applications. I've added support for views loaded by AJAX https://github.com/tapquo/Lungo.js

fuubar-cucumber, creator

Cucumber progress bar formatter https://github.com/martinciu/fuubar-cucumber

Projects

Creator of Postcatcher, the HTTP POST requests testing application

Hosted tool for testing and debugging WebHooks. Technologies used: Node.js, Coffescript, Express, Pusher, MongoDB, jQuery. Project is not maintained anymore. http://postcatcher.in

Volunteer

Coach at Rails Girls Barcelona, 03/2015 - 07/2015

Rails Girls is a free workshops for women without prior experience in programming. I was teaching basics of Ruby and Ruby on Rails during weekend workshop as well as on ongoing bi-weekly meet-ups.

Education

Gdansk University of Technology, Poland; 3 of 5 years completed, 2000 - 2003

Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Informatics

Achievements

Node Knockout 2011

Created PostCatcher - the HTTP POST requests testing application. Hosted tool for testing and debugging WebHooks. It took 5th place in the Solo category. Technologies used Node.js, Coffescript, Express, Pusher, MongoDB, jQuery. http://postcatcher.in/

Rails Rumble 2010

Participated in RailsRumble 2010. Created tool for monitoring opinions about brands on twitter. It is no longer maintained.

Languages

- English professional working proficiency
- Spanish beginner
- Polish mother tongue

phone.+48 501 009 207
email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com
linkedin: linkedin.com/in/martinciu
github: github.com/martinciu

location: Warsaw, Poland